WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
I assume Drewe knows we're coming.
Yes. I sent a note yesterday.
Have the pigs recovered,
do you think?
They look in good shape to me,
after the shock of their arrival.
But why didn't he check to see
... they all had water
before he left for the night?
Maybe he thought a full trough
was enough.
He wasn't to know
they'd kick it over.
Mr Branson is right.
He should have made sure.
You would have done.
Where did you learn about pigs?
We've always had pigs at Yew Tree,
m'lady.
Not many,
but enough to learn their ways.
Thank heavens you did.
So, have you found a man
to take over?
Not yet.
First, we'd like to know
if you'd want the job.
Me? You mean I'm to manage the pigs
for the estate, as well as my farm?
It's asking a lot.
I can do it. If you're sure.
Let's give it a try,
see how we get on.
I'm very grateful, m'lady.
This is the second good turn
I've received from your family,
and I just hope
I can pay back a favour one day.
How nice of you.
I don't know if it's much of
a favour.
We're giving you a lot of work.
Work's like old age, m'lady.
The worst thing in the world
except for the alternative.
It's only me.
I always feel that greeting betrays
such a lack of self worth.
How are we today?
My dear, please stop talking to me
as if I were a child past hope.
Very well. How are you feeling?
Like Doctor Manette.
If I don't get out of this house
soon,
I shall remember nothing
but my number.
Then why don't we walk to the Abbey
this afternoon, if it's fine?
Hear how Robert's getting on
in America.
Is it really called
the Teapot Dome scandal?
It seems so unlikely.
What's it about?
What is it always about?
Bribery and corruption.
Taking money
to allow private companies
to drill for oil on Government land.
Mr Levinson has
one of these companies?
I assume so.
Have you ever met him?
Once. At the wedding.
And once was quite enough.
I can't tell you how thrilling
that sounds. I'll be waiting for you.
We'll have such a lovely day.
Who was that?
No-one. Just a friend.
You have to pull your weight
with the bazaar.
It seems to have crept up on me.
Does Cousin Robert usually do it?
He does. Half the village
hates the other half
and only he can stop them
tearing each other's throats out.
I admire that. It's a real skill.
Mr Molesley, erm,
is it true that you were a valet?
For the late Mr Crawley?
And butler to his mother
before that.
I've come down in the world.
You can climb up again.
Maybe. But life kicks the stuffing
out of you sometimes, doesn't it?
Oh, I've had my stuffing kicked out
more than once.
I've woken and wondered
if there was any point to it.
Yet here I am,
lady's maid to a countess.
So, it can happen.
Now you've made me curious.
I'm curious about something
and you could help me.
Do you know if Mr and Mrs Bates
have had a falling out?
Mr and Mrs Bates?
That doesn't sound very likely.
Can I ask you
to put that machine away?
We'll be laying for tea in a minute.
Of course.
Is everything ready
for the servants' tea?
Oh, is it just me or do we have
twice the bills we used to?
Ivy, this is for you.
Did you find those oyster shells
for the kettle?
I've put them in. About time.
It were full of scale.
What in God's name was that about?
Don't rise to it. She just wants us
to think her life's interesting.
Anything interesting?
I'm reading about County Politics.
They're looking for candidates
for the local Council.
Why don't you put yourself forward?
But what are my politics these days?
I'm not sure.
You could always read a bit
about it.
You won't find many books
on the Liberal ideals in this room.
And nothing at all about Socialism.
If you're serious about driving me
to Thirsk tomorrow,
perhaps we might find some then.
Are you better now, Granny?
If you'd been to see me, you'd know.
Don't bully me. I'm not up to it.
No. Rosamund told me.
When? What did she say?
Only that you needed
a little cherishing, that's all.
So Mr Drewe's accepted your offer.
I'm so pleased.
The Drewes have been at
Yew Tree Farm for many years.
I suppose you think
that's sentimental bosh, Mr Blake.
Don't be too hard on him, Granny.
Mr Blake has a softer side
than we first gave him credit for.
I'm relieved to hear I am redeemed
before we leave for London.
I hope I'm forgiven, too.
I know you thought me very snobbish
when you first arrived.
I don't blame you. Given my work,
I came as an envoy of the enemy.
Are we too early?
Bring them in, Nanny.
I don't think anyone will mind.
Your Papa might,
but he isn't here to complain.
One moment, darling,
while Mummy puts away her cup.
Oh, here, let me. Hello there.
Oh, it's all right.
He's turning into quite a bruiser.
Yes, and I must go.
Stay and have some dinner, Mama.
You needn't change.
No. Thank you, my dear, but no.
You should change and I should go.
When you go down, can you give
a message to Mrs Hughes?
Of course.
Lord Gillingham telephoned today.
He wants to break his journey home.
Tomorrow night.
He'll be here again?
You're right.
I shouldn't encourage him,
but I couldn't think what to say
to persuade him not to.
Do you think me very feeble?
It's not that, m'lady.
Then what is it?
Anna?
It's nothing to bother you with.
Please bother me.
If I did, you'd have to promise
to do nothing about it.
But how does this concern
Lord Gillingham?
It doesn't, m'lady. It's nothing to
do with Lord Gillingham himself.
But then...
It's his man, m'lady.
His servant, Mr Green,
who travels with him.
Oh, my God.
But the police ought to -
No!
I must tell Lord Gillingham.
No, m'lady, you promised.
Mr Bates doesn't know it was him.
But the more he comes here,
the more likely it is
that Mr Bates will find out.
Then I'll telephone him and tell him
not to come, or not to bring Green.
I'm frightened every time Mr Green
and Mr Bates are in the same room.
You think, if he guesses,
he'll do something.
And if he does, they'll hang him.
Or lock him up
and throw away the key.
Jimmy, the savouries can go in
and Daisy'll bring up the sauce.
And now perhaps you can explain why
you have apparently been
under hypnosis since dinner began.
I don't know what you mean.
Yes, you do.
Mooning about
like a sloth under water.
Well?
You know I had a letter earlier?
It were from Alfred.
It seems his father died
and Alfred's coming up
for the funeral.
Oh, I am sorry.
That's not all.
He says he wants to marry me.
What?! Just like that?
He says the way I behaved
towards him when he were last here
made him hope
that things had changed between us.
Well, you were very friendly.
That's not all.
He wants me to leave Downton
and go up to London.
He says he can find me a job.
Blimey.
He puts a lot in a letter,
does Alfred.
They're serving the savouries.
We'll talk about it later.
Now, er,
put the water on for the coffee.
That's enough for one day, surely.
You can finish them tomorrow.
Shall we walk back to the cottage?
The others are going to bed.
What were you saying to Mrs Hughes?
Just that Lord Gillingham's
asked himself for the night again.
He can't stay away.
Yes. It's a bit of a tangle.
Do you think she's sweet on him?
They're sweet on each other, but
it's not as simple as that, is it?
Then there's Mr Blake.
I thought she didn't like him.
She didn't. At first.
Anyway,
they can sort it out between them.
And Mr Green.
He'll be coming back.
Have you gone off him?
Why do you say that?
You liked him so much
when he first came.
You thought he was funny.
Did I?
I can't remember.
So, you're pleased with Mr Drewe?
I am. And I'm very pleased with the
pigs too. They're a grand addition.
When they've settled,
you ought to consider dairy.
Another job
for the splendid Mr Drewe.
I think he IS rather splendid.
He seems to want to make farming
at Downton his life's work.
That's very lyrical.
Lady Rosamund Painswick
is on the telephone, m'lady.
Do you have anything planned
for today?
Some shopping. That's all.
Do you think I should write
and give him my answer?
If you're sure about it.
I don't want to marry Alfred.
Then there's no more to be said.
Even if I did, I wouldn't care to
tie myself down yet.
How do I know
what life has in store?
You're a very optimistic generation,
I'll say that.
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
I wish you'd say, cos it's clear
as day you're up to something.
None of us know
when Papa's coming back.
But yes,
we must tell her before then.
In fact, I've had an idea.
Well, if you're sure, then why not?
We've already got friends of Mary
staying. Ring with the train time.
'Bye-bye dear.'
Who was that?
Aunt Rosamund.
She's coming to see how Granny is.
Why are you down so early?
I've got to check some figures with
Tom before he goes into Thirsk.
Quite the businesswoman.
We must rise to life's challenges.
Yes, I suppose we must.
Let's meet in the book shop
in ten minutes.
I've got some letters to post.
I'll see you there.
Thank you.
Good day.
Don't, don't do that.
You mustn't be so self-conscious.
A black singer with the daughter of
a marquess in a Yorkshire town?
Why should we attract any attention?
Well, that's their problem.
It doesn't have to be ours.
I'm terribly puffed
that you made the journey.
Me too, but...
But what?
I hope we're brave enough for this.
Of course we are!
Isn't it time people knew
there are bigger and better values
than the mean-spirited ones
they live by?
Does Lady Grantham know
you're out for the day?
It won't matter
as long as I'm back for dinner.
Are you playing tonight?
I wouldn't be here if I were.
I can stay for as long as you want.
Well, I want you to stay forever,
but six o'clock will do.
You're not very talkative.
What's the matter?
I was thinking about
a couple of people
who are in a situation
which will cause trouble.
Will it make them unhappy?
It's hard to say.
It'll make some people unhappy.
I thought I might make some coffee.
Would you like a cup?
No, thank you.
It's just coffee. You won't have to
surrender any of your independence.
Er, you win.
Er, milk but no sugar.
Miss Baxter,
I do know what it's like,
to feel fragile.
I've felt fragile my whole life.
You'll have realised by now that,
down here,
we don't much care for Mr Barrow,
which may offend you.
I'm not...offended.
But I wish you'd give us credit for
making up our own minds about you.
Hello.
This is Miss...
Bunting. Sarah Bunting.
And this is Mrs Crawley.
I met Miss Bunting at the political
meeting you sent me to. In Ripon.
Ah, so that was the reason.
Why do you say that?
He wasn't exactly enthralled
to the cause of the Liberals.
Though I'm not now convinced
by his Socialism. Why not?
I didn't know then that you were
the land agent and son-in-law
of our local milord.
I'm surprised I'm so famous.
Won't you defend your principles?
No, not now.
Then I will. Mr Branson
is a keen political thinker.
He proves this by not being afraid
to question his own beliefs.
Very eloquent.
I'd stay to argue, but I'm late.
Do you live around here?
I work here.
At the school.
It was nice to see you again.
Hello, Miss.
Hello.
She knows her own mind.
Yes, I think she does.
Apparently, he left the Dalrymples
straight after breakfast,
so I missed him when I telephoned.
You did your best.
I am so sorry.
Come in!
No tails? You know Granny's coming.
Oh, God, is she? I didn't realise.
No, don't change. It's time
she learned about the real world.
A phrase with more than
one definition.
Can I have a word?
I've seen something,
and I'm not saying
there's anything wrong about it,
but I'd feel uncomfortable
if I kept it to myself.
I'm all ears.
This morning in Thirsk,...
I saw Rose.
Yes, she was shopping.
No, she was not shopping.
She was...meeting a man.
I saw her as she reached up
to stroke his cheek.
Oh, golly. Who is it this time?
It was Jack Ross -
the singer with the band
who came up for your father's party.
Well, that's it. I've told you
and I have nothing more to add.
Anna?
She's told you, then?
Don't give me away Mrs Hughes,
please.
I can get through it.
My maid said
you were waiting in here.
Everyone else
is in the drawing room.
I know,
but I thought you'd want to hear.
I think I know how
I can keep the baby.
What? How?
There's a tenant farmer,
whose family has been at Downton for
years. I'm sure he can be trusted.
This is very reckless.
Well, what would you suggest?
I'd suggest that we go away,
you and me, on an extended trip
to...somewhere.
Then the baby can be adopted by
a childless couple in that country,
wherever it may be,
and they are made very happy.
And the baby is happy,
and you are...
..well, if not happy, at least free.
But I wouldn't be part of
its growing up?
You wouldn't be part of its life.
Why is my idea so reckless?
Oh my dear, where shall I start?
Suppose the farmer talks?
Suppose you're seen
visiting his home,
which I presume is the idea?
Suppose the baby looks like you
and people in the village notice?
Suppose you talk?
I left a list somewhere
that I need for Mrs Patmore.
You know Lord Gillingham is here.
Er, yes. We were just chatting.
We're coming now.
I'm desperately trying to take
control of the bazaar.
Talk about herding cats.
I'll stay and help if you want.
You may regret saying that.
And while I'm here, we can discuss
a plan that I'd like to get settled.
I've always wanted to speak
better French than I do,
so I thought I'd take a few months
off, go to...Switzerland
and really learn it.
I see. Not France?
You know what the French are like.
While Switzerland is so clean.
And they have wonderful hospitals...
in case we get ill.
We? I wondered if Edith might like
to come. Keep me company.
I'll pay.
What do you have to say about that?
I'd like to.
Goodness. Oh. Well,...why not?
Golly, life is full of surprises.
But I'd better check to see that
the young men are keeping the peace.
So we won't have to tell her?
I don't think we need to, do you?
Can you really afford to spend four
months reading novels in the Alps?
Why ask the question
when the decision has been made?
Come on, we ought to join the others.
Have you been wandering round
Scotland since we saw you?
I have. I was on the Spey.
I did a tour of the cousinage,
then a wedding in Ayrshire.
I've enjoyed myself.
It gave me time to think for once.
Oh, what about particularly?
My life, I suppose.
Everyone should, from time to time.
Oh, I can't agree. In my experience
it's a dangerous occupation.
Dangerous?
Well, no life appears rewarding
if you think too much about it.
I gather you've launched into pigs
these days.
Yes. And their arrival
was quite the adventure,
in which Mr Blake and Mary
were the hero and heroine.
Is this what you wouldn't tell me
when I was last here?
Only because I didn't want to make
too much of it.
Lady Mary was perfectly splendid.
Lady Mary IS perfectly splendid.
Really, Charles,
are you a pig expert, as well?
He was that night, thank heaven.
Rosamund and Edith
have some exciting news.
What's that?
We're going on a sabbatical
so we can really improve our French.
The only thing I ever learned from
my governess was how to say
"please", "thank you"
and "I have a temperature."
Very useful if one were travelling.
Do you remember her, Mama?
She was always in tears.
Oh, poor Mademoiselle. Her life was
full of... complications.
I think she quite enjoyed it,
though.
But why you?
You don't want to learn French.
Or is this an incognito search
for the missing Mr Gregson?
Don't tease her.
It's much more serious than that.
Thank you, Tom.
If you must know,
I fancy getting away for a bit.
Oh. Like Lord Gillingham,
thinking his way around
the Highlands.
I like Scotland, me. At least,
I would if I'd ever been there.
Well, I've had a bellyful of heather
and no mistake.
Aren't you going to fight back,
Mrs Hughes?
Mr Green can think what he likes.
So you're glad
you're on your way to London?
It'll be all I can do to stop
singing when I get in the car.
Where do you live when you're there?
His lordship's got a set at Albany.
Is that handy for the West End?
You're joking.
Piccadilly one end,
Saville Row the other.
Oh, you lucky tyke.
I AM a lucky tyke.
Do you like London, Miss Baxter?
Not particularly.
I lived there at one time
but it didn't work for me.
What about you, Anna? Do you fancy
a taste of Mr Green's life?
I'm happy where I am, thank you.
Rose was badgering me
about going up to London again
but she's been enough lately,
don't you think? I certainly do.
After all, she's got to have
some novelty when we bring her out.
Quite right.
She can help with the bazaar.
That'll take her mind off things.
Trouble is, parenting an adult
- especially when it's someone
else's daughter -
is really a matter of
mutual agreement.
There's a limit to how much
one can simply forbid.
Sshh. Here she is.
Actually, I want a word with her.
Rose, darling. Can I drag you into
my room for a moment?
Anna, could you leave us
for a minute?
Of course.
This is early for you to go to bed.
I had rather a tiring day.
So I heard.
Well, I heard you had
an interesting day.
Whether or not it was tiring,
you know better than I.
Who told you?
My dear, all I want is for you
not to lose control of your life.
I love him.
And I won't listen to any
imperialist nonsense
about racial purity
and how he should be horsewhipped
for daring to dream.
Don't you know me better than that?
I'm going to marry him, Mary.
I don't care what it costs
and I won't keep it a secret.
Not once I've told Mummy.
I want to see her face crumble
when she finds out.
Rose!
I feel we're driving you away.
Oh, hardly. We're in grave danger
of outstaying our welcome.
If Tony hadn't offered us a lift
we'd be here forever.
I hope you'll be back soon.
Good luck with your bazaar.
Can't you stay and lend me a hand?
Don't tempt me.
I'm so grateful for your advice
and wisdom.
And not least for the very practical
and muddy pig rescue.
Glad to be of service, m'lady.
Are you going straight there?
We might stop for some lunch...
It's kind of you
to give them a lift.
Pure self interest. I couldn't leave
Charles here, alone with you.
Will you let me see you
when you're next down south?
What would be the point, Tony?
I'm never going to be your mistress.
That's not me at all.
I've made up my mind
to call off the engagement.
Does Mabel know?
Not yet.
I haven't been in London since...
and I must tell her face to face.
Of course you must, but I wish
you'd think seriously before you do.
You mean you're going to
turn me down again.
I've told you
I'm not on the market, Tony.
I'm not free.
Sometimes I almost wish I were,
but I'm not.
And that's all there is to it.
Oh, you have been incredibly kind
to put up with us for so long.
We'll miss you.
The house will seem rather empty.
If it were my choice,
I should never be away from here.
Can I ask you one thing?
How do you feel about your man?
I'm still not very keen on him.
Why?
We'd better get started.
So, this really is goodbye.
Not for long, I hope.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
I'm sorry to see them go.
Not as sorry as Mary.
What's a group noun for suitors?
What do you think? A desire?
A desire of suitors. Very good.
If you're going to talk nonsense,
I have better things to do.
I've posted the letter.
Well, he'll probably still come.
He's got to be in Yorkshire for
the funeral, whatever you said.
Whatever she said to who?
Oh, just tell me.
I know you've got a secret,
and if you're trying to spare
my feelings it's not working.
Alfred's written.
His father's died,
so he's coming for the burial.
He wants to look in and see us all.
See us all, or see her?
Alfred's asked me to marry him.
But she's turned him down.
So his heart's broken properly
this time. Are you satisfied now?
Why don't we leave the subject
there? We don't want to fall out.
We can't fall out,
we've never fallen in!
So they got off in good order.
I wonder how long it'll take
for them all to propose to Mary.
Isn't Lord Gillingham engaged?
He's supposed to be, but he still
seems as keen as mustard.
Well, that is very interesting.
But it's not why I asked you here.
Oh?
No.
I want to know what you were doing
at Downton.
I don't understand.
Why shouldn't I come to Downton?
I grew up here.
I see I'll have to take
the slow path.
You telephone to say
Edith is to be cherished,
but you don't say why.
Didn't I?
No.
Next, you invite yourself to Downton
and reveal at dinner
that you and Edith are retreating
to the continent for several months
so you can improve your French.
Yes.
Rosamund has no interest in French.
If she wishes to be understood
by a foreigner, she shouts.
That's not fair.
Isn't it time
one of you told me the truth?
If I told you the truth, Granny,
you would never speak to me again.
Then you HAVE told me the truth.
But I would like to hear it
enunciated more clearly.
Right. Now, we must all look lively.
They're starting to set up
the stalls for the bazaar today
and her ladyship will need
all hands on deck.
James, Mr Molesley, if you could
both keep an eye on things.
Do we get paid extra?
No,
but if you play your cards right,
you'll avoid a clip round the ear.
I'll ask Mrs Patmore for some
refreshment for the village people.
This is an early warning
that they're coming to set up
the stalls for Saturday,
so we'd better have sandwiches
and beer at the ready.
As I feared. Alfred's looking in on
Saturday on his way back to London.
So he'll be here for the bazaar.
He does know
there's no hope with Ivy?
Well, that's why he's written to me.
But he says he wants to see her.
It's not going to be very easy
for Daisy.
I thought I'd give her the day off.
You won't mind, will you?
If you think it best. It's you
who'll do the extra work, not me.
What a nightmare.
The man selling ices is ill
so I've got to find another.
The grocers from Easingwold
and Malton can't be side by side,
and I've got to decide
the house menus with Mrs Patmore.
I'll do that. Tend to the bazaar.
Are you sure? Because if you are...
I'm sure.
When's Cousin Robert coming back?
I don't know. I wish I did.
We've had no word from him in days.
What is it?
I've got to tell someone,
or I'll just explode.
Tell someone what?
Oh, Mary.
What do you think?
I'm engaged!
But what was so urgent?
First,
can you join me for luncheon today?
Well, I suppose so. I ought to go
back and tell Mrs Field. Why?
I've got Lord Merton coming.
Mary's Godfather?
Mm. It was fixed years ago,
but now Robert's off on his travels,
Cora is too busy...
and Mary's chucked.
For what reason?
Suddenly she has to be in London.
I think Rosamund's still here.
Oh, no, she can't stand him.
I could ask Edith.
She might be free.
Oh, I hope so.
I'm a feeble substitute
for the entire Crawley family.
Mmm, yes,
but you're better than nothing.
How warming you make that sound.
Oh, I'm ever so glad to find you.
Can you help me do these?
What's the rush?
Lady Mary has to go to London.
Why?
I'm not sure.
But she wants me to go with her.
Of course.
When will you be back?
Tomorrow evening, but we'll be late.
It's not fair.
I stop you going to New York
and then I set off for London.
Don't be silly.
Come in.
Mr Carson, I'd like to go into York
tomorrow. I hope you don't mind.
You've got no duties here.
Why should I mind?
I'll set off first thing,
if you've no objection.
Be my guest, Mr Bates.
I still don't understand why
you're not in NEW York,
so I can hardly object to York.
Enjoy yourself.
Very good. Well done, ladies.
Can I have a go?
It's not ready yet.
Anyway, you're a bit of a shrimp,
aren't you?
I'm a shrimp with muscles, me.
We'll find that out on Saturday.
I've never had a go on one of those.
It's not your sort of thing.
More sandwiches and more beer.
It's like a plague of locusts.
Busy, Mr Molesley?
I like the bazaar.
I always enjoy it. I hope you will.
Can't you help her to, Mr Molesley?
Oh, get off with you,
you cheeky devil.
Alfred's coming Saturday, in't he?
How do you know that?
I heard you and Mrs Hughes talking.
Well I, I were going to mention it,
because I wondered
if you'd rather be away.
What about all the work?
Oh, it's mostly done by then.
If you'd rather avoid him,
I won't mind.
Could I go and see Mr Mason?
That's a good idea.
Stay away as late as you like.
Just to be safe.
But why the urgency?
I can't explain, but I swear
if you knew, you'd approve.
What this? What's happened?
Mary has to go to London.
It's no big thing.
I'll be back tomorrow night.
Can I come?
No.
Well, why not?
Because Mama needs you here.
Goodbye, then. Bye, Rose.
Do you want to stay at the house?
I'll telephone if you do.
Could you? You're an angel.
I told Mead he could visit
his sister in Swindon,
but they'll do the best they can.
Thank you.
How mysterious.
Is anything wrong?
The car's packed in,
my friend's gone for help.
Would you like me to have a look?
I don't want to hold you up.
I've no appointment.
I was on my way to Skipton
to see some suppliers
and compare prices.
How impressive.
I thought that when the agent
was a cousin or son-in-law,
he had free shooting for life,
but others did the work.
To quote my wife's grandmother,
you've been reading
Socialist newspapers again.
You should know.
Is this wise?
You've heard some of my story,
but not all of it.
I came to Downton
to be the chauffeur.
Now...
That was a splendid luncheon.
Quite a change for me.
Oh, I can't believe that.
It's true.
I eat nothing but nursery food.
Perhaps you need a new cook.
It's not her fault.
I never know what to order.
A husband is told so often
he's going to die first,
you never think you're going to
have to manage on your own.
I doubt Doctor Crawley
would have managed any better.
I'm so interested he was a doctor.
I wanted to study medicine myself,
but my father didn't really...
Didn't see it as a profession
for a gentleman.
I don't believe he'd have gone that
far.
But he didn't think it
quite suitable for a peer, no.
I must try and find an example
to rebut that.
Well, I must be going.
Let me take you. My car's outside.
I can easily walk.
I'd like to. Please.
Then...thank you.
I should go too, Granny.
No. Stay.
I want to speak to you.
So were you still the chauffeur
when you married?
That's a long story.
Everything with you's a long story.
That one had a happy ending.
For a time, anyway.
I know she died.
I'm so sorry.
She must have been a very unusual
and independent person.
You could say that again.
It's nice that they asked you
to stay, to make your life here.
I have a little daughter,
and it seemed the right thing.
Still, it makes me take
a kinder view of the family.
Oh? What do you have against them?
Nothing.
But, as a rule,
I don't really warm to their type.
I don't believe in types.
I believe in people.
Now give it a try.
I really am very grateful.
Thank you.
I don't often say it,
but Rosamund is right.
I do not know this Mr...Mr Drewe,...
..but even if he is everything
you say,
to keep the child here
would be like a permanent sword of
Damocles, inches from your head.
But I can't bear the thought
of giving it away.
And is it right
that it should grow up Swiss?
Well, Switzerland
has everything to offer,...
..except perhaps conversation.
And one can learn to live
without that.
And if Michael turns up?
Well, if you want my advice,
start again.
Now, I will pay for everything.
Aunt Rosamund said she would.
You'll be quite enough in her debt
as it is.
Take any more,
and she'll start exacting
annual tribute.
What do your sons do?
I assume they do something.
Remember I met Larry at that dinner?
Ah, don't remind me.
They do work.
Larry's in banking
and Tim's in the diplomatic,
so nothing very startling there.
What about yours?
Matthew was a lawyer.
Oh, has he given it up?
He's...
He's dead.
I thought you would know that.
Oh, good God.
I'm terribly sorry. I... I'd
forgotten for a moment who you were.
Don't worry. Please.
How is Mary? I do wish
I could have seen her today.
Well, slow to start with, but now
she's on her way, which I'm glad of.
I heard they were well suited.
Yes.
They were happy,
which makes the parting worse,
but gives you strength in the end,
as we know.
You maybe. Not me.
Lady Merton and I were not exactly
meant to be together.
We struggled on, of course,
as everyone did in those days,
but I'm not sure now
how sensible it was.
I envy you, your wonderful memories,
but I can't pretend to match them.
Is Mr Ross here yet?
Who shall I say is calling?
Rose's cousin.
♪ Da-da-da-da-da
♪ Da-da-da-da
♪ Da-ba-da-ba-da
♪ Da-da-dee-dee-dee
♪ Da-da-da-da
♪ Da-da- ♪
Lady Mary. Huh.
I was wondering if it would be you.
How did you know
someone was coming?
Rose telephoned.
She said she'd told you
we were about to set the date.
I just made some tea.
Would you like a cup?
Thank you.
I suppose you're here to say that
Lord Flintshire
would find the prospect of
a black son-in-law preposterous.
And your father would agree.
To be fair to Papa,
he'd find your being a band singer
even harder to swallow
than your colour.
Mr Ross, are you sure about this?
Marriage is a challenge,
even when everyone wants it.
Even if everyone prays
you'll be happy.
You mean in our case, they'll all be
trying to pull us apart.
Every hour of every day.
Tell me, do you think she loves you?
Don't you believe in us?
I believe in you.
I'm not so sure about her.
She may love you a bit,
but mostly I'd say
she wants to shock her mother,
whom incidentally, she hates.
That's what my mother said.
She said Rose
must be proving some point.
You and my mother
have a lot in common.
Tell me honestly: Do you think you
can survive what they'll do to you?
Because I don't believe Rose could.
It may come as something
of a relief for you to hear that
I will not be marrying Rose.
You won't?
No.
I've enjoyed her dreams.
I think she's more than you allow.
But?
I don't want to spoil her life.
I don't want to watch
while people point at her and jeer.
I love her.
I want her to be happy.
So you'll end it?
Yes.
I should probably have stopped it
sooner, but at any rate,...
..I'm stopping it now.
So will you tell Rose, or shall I?
I'll tell her.
I'll write to her.
She'll get it tomorrow.
It doesn't mean I think it's right.
I wouldn't give in if we lived in
even a slightly better world.
It may surprise you, Mr Ross,
but if we lived in a better world,
I wouldn't want you to.
I've been downstairs, m'lady.
They're making dinner for you now.
I don't want a lot.
I've told them that.
How are you?
Much as I was yesterday.
Much as I will be tomorrow.
Anna,
I've decided to see
Lord Gillingham.
I'm sorry, but I must do something.
I'll telephone
and suggest we meet for luncheon.
Then I'll ask him straight out
to dismiss his valet.
I won't say why.
That makes me so nervous.
Don't be.
No-one needs to know the reason.
Green simply won't be back
at Downton again.
Is Bates going to challenge
Lord Gillingham
as to why he has a different valet?
I suppose not.
So you have nothing to fear
if he pays us a visit.
And will he, m'lady?
Er, dinner's on the table, m'lady.
I'm not sure Mead would have put it
like that, but thank you.
So, we decorate the stalls today.
You all know the drill.
And remember,
anything shabby
shows Downton in a bad light.
And we can't have that.
No, Mrs Hughes, we can't.
Will you come?
It'll give you a chance to meet
a few people from the village.
Is it not just the estate workers?
Oh, no, no.
The whole area gets behind
the Church bazaar.
You're very lucky, you know.
Nobody's ever called me that.
Least of all myself.
To grow up in a village where
people know and like you,
where your family's respected.
Plenty would give an eye for that.
I'm not used to feeling lucky.
Well, you should be.
Are we trying for a colour scheme?
Goodness, I thought I'd be down
before anyone.
Oh, no. This is one task
that demands an early start.
The tent's up for the tea.
They're fetching tables and chairs
from the barn.
Don't let them mess up the grass
when they drive them back.
Rose!
One, two, three, lift.
Oh!
I can manage.
Rose...
Should you be doing this?
Why? What are you afraid of?
That I'll lose the baby?
So they've made you
a beast of burden now?
That's right.
And they're not taking advantage?
Are they ready for these?
Give me those. James!
Could you take these to the tent,
please?
May I present Miss Bunting?
She teaches at the village school.
I'm very interested in the school.
You know Lady Grantham?
Of course.
It's nice to meet you,
but I'm afraid I must get on.
So that's the great Countess
of Grantham.
It is. Another beast of burden.
I'll sack him if you insist,
but tell me why. It's only fair.
I don't know if it's fair
or unfair, but I can't.
Not even a hint?
I've said what I can.
He's done something
you'd find...abhorrent.
Well, you win.
But it does seem mean,
even if I don't like him very much.
You wouldn't think it mean
if you knew the truth.
Well, I believe you.
I love you and I believe you.
Have you spoken to Mabel?
I have.
But I wasn't going to bring it up.
Why not?
I don't want to twist your arm.
And I know that you won't make
a decision until it suits you.
How did she take it?
I'm so pleased you asked.
I think the answer is
with real style.
Well, I'm glad.
And now, can you get the bill?
I'm terribly late.
I must catch the last train.
It's the Church bazaar tomorrow.
I won't give up, Mary.
Not until you walk down the aisle
with another man,
and very possibly not even then.
I find that both irritating
and beguiling in equal measure.
Should I take comfort from that?
Take what you like.
I'm going.
And do what I ask with Green,...
..and please let me know
when you've done it.
You sent for me?
I wouldn't put it like that.
I just wondered if you might be free.
Oh. Your wish is my command.
These came this morning
from Lord Merton. As a thank you.
That was kind of him.
But what part do I play in it?
They're for you.
For me? Surely not.
Yes, he sent me some too,
these came with them.
I read the card.
He asks forgiveness
for his tactlessness.
Was he tactless?
He didn't mean to be tactless.
How nice.
Mmm.
Very nice.
Quite...quite surprising,
but very nice.
I'm just going up
to see if they need anything more.
Can you leave these
for one of the hall boys?
I'll do them, Mr Carson.
I don't mind.
You took your time in York.
Yes, it was quite a long day.
What were you up to?
Oh, this and that.
One, two, three, go!
Lovely to see you again.
Thank you very much.
You got his letter, then?
You're so disappointing, Mary.
I thought you understood,
and you're just like my mother.
No, I'm not. But I understand this -
if you're going to complicate your
life, do it for the right reasons.
James, I'm putting the tea tent
in your charge.
Make sure they don't
run out of anything.
But her ladyship said
we were to enjoy ourselves.
Let us consider this.
She wants you to enjoy yourself,
I want you to run the tent.
Now, which of us can make your life
more uncomfortable?
Mr Molesley.
Mr Molesley! Mr Molesley!
Tell those people
where they're supposed to park.
Wait a minute. It's his lordship!
His lordship's back!
Tell the others!
James!
How can you be here?!
Why didn't you send a message?
We would have made such a fuss!
You're a beast!
Oh, not quite a beast, I hope.
I wanted to surprise you
and I think I have.
Papa, you should have let us know!
When did you get in?
This morning.
I'd forgotten about the bazaar.
I was right not to distract you all
from your labours.
What happened to Uncle Harold?
A reprimand, but nothing more.
So it was worth your going.
I don't think I made
a bit of difference,
but let's hold on to that fiction.
How was it?
Interesting.
Very modern...and very interesting.
How's it been here?
Not very interesting
and not very modern.
Carson.
Hello, Bates. Have you missed me?
Because I've certainly missed you.
Good to see you back, m'lord.
You're back.
I can't believe it.
If you knew how many times
I'd imagined this scene.
This is a treat. It's been a while.
I'm sorry if I've stayed away.
Nay, no apologies. Not from you.
Not here.
You're my daughter-in-law,
you're all that I've got left
of my son.
Whether you come here or not,
this is your home.
I do love it when I come.
I'm glad.
That's it.
Oh, there you are, Alfred. Nice
to see you. Have a glass of this.
Is Ivy about?
I'm just here.
Thank you.
How was the funeral?
Was well attended.
So that's something
for my mother to hold on to.
I read your letter.
I'm sorry if I hurt your feelings.
No, I'm sorry.
I got the wrong end of the stick
when I were last up here,
but it were my mistake.
All you did was...try and give me
a nice welcome,
and you can't feel sorry for that.
We can part as friends?
We can, as far as I'm concerned.
Is Daisy here?
I wanted to see if she and I could
be friends an' all before I go.
She's gone to Mr Mason's farm
for the day.
She won't be back till late.
Oh.
Daisy, are you here
to avoid seeing Alfred?
Ivy's turned him down again,
so he won't come back after today.
What does Mrs Patmore say about it?
To stay away so I don't meet him.
I would advise against that.
But why?
I thought you'd be glad
if I stayed a bit longer.
I wish you'd stay and never leave,
and I hope you will one day,
but Mrs Patmore's wrong.
Daisy, there won't be too many people
that you love in your life,
and he's one.
I don't know what I feel about him.
Not now.
Even so, you need to say goodbye
to this young man,
with nothing jagged,
nothing harsh, between you.
I couldn't think of the words.
We'll find them together.
And er, we'll get you back to Downton
in time.
Are you bearing up?
In here.
I'm never going to see Michael again,
am I?
If you want to go out there
and look for him, I'll support you.
They've already done all that.
Police and private detectives
and everything.
Well, then you must be patient.
Sometimes I feel that God
doesn't want me to be happy.
My dear, all life
is a series of problems
which we must try and solve.
First one, then the next,
and the next,...
..until at last we die.
Why don't you get us an ice cream?
Yes. That should sort it out.
Isn't that Lord Gillingham?
What? It can't be. Where?
What does Miss Lane Fox think
about it? That's what I wonder.
I agree. He's the most unconvincing
fiance I've ever come across.
Perhaps she doesn't know.
If we know, she knows.
You can count on that.
Green. But how could he be dead?
I'm only telling you what they told
me.
That he was in Piccadilly and he...
slipped or stumbled
and fell into the road.
I don't know what to say.
It just seemed so odd
after our conversation yesterday
that I felt that I should...
bring you the news myself.
Can you explain to me now
why you wanted him sacked?
No.
Hello, Tony. Heavens,
what a gathering of the clans
today's turning out to be.
Would you excuse me for a moment?
I don't suppose it's a good sign
to find you back at Downton?
Not really. Not this time.
You mean he fell into the road
and he was hit? Yesterday?
By a bus or lorry, apparently.
And someone saw this?
The pavement was crowded.
Lots of people saw it.
That's a relief.
What do you mean?
Nothing. I don't mean anything.
Mary!
Did your mother warn you
I was coming?
She did.
Why are you back in Yorkshire
so soon?
I'd no sooner got back than I was
despatched to a tenant farmers'
convention in Whitby.
But it's over now,
so I'll go home from here.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
It's an odd question.
Go on.
If you thought a man was involved
in a crime, or an incident,
but you didn't blame him,
in fact you thought right
was on his side,
what would you do?
It's a bit theoretical
for an opinion.
But you don't believe he was wrong?
No.
Well, I'm guessing in the dark,
but...I suspect I would say nothing.
That isn't fair. It's weighted.
Go on. You have a go, Mr Molesley.
No, no, I won't manage it
if Jimmy can't.
Try. I want to see it.
Well done!
That was cheating.
Well, it...it's in the arms.
It's all to do with the swing,
and the swing is in the arms.
So, Miss Baxter,
anything to tell me about life
since I've been away?
No. Nothing's happened.
I'll find out if it has, you know.
Leave her alone, Mr Barrow.
We don't want any bullying
brought back from overseas.
Do we, Miss Baxter?
Now, are there any stalls
you'd still like to see?
God, what a relief
to be able to drink in public
without a policeman pouncing.
Down with Prohibition.
You can't mean you never had
a drink all the time you were there.
Harold has his uses.
I suppose he does.
And let us hope
they both leave us in peace.
A slim hope, I'm afraid.
Martha wants to bring him over next
summer for Rose's coming out ball.
Why?
She says she wants to see another
London Season before she dies.
Oh!
You're still here. Thank goodness.
I caught an early bus, but it was
delayed. I thought I'd missed you.
I'm off to the station now, Daisy.
And I won't be back.
My dad's gone and mother's moving
to Crewe to be nearer my sister,
so I'm glad you're here
to say goodbye. I really am.
I've brought you a present.
Mr Mason's made you
a basket full of things.
Rolls and cheese and ham,
and jams and pickles,
and he's put some cider in too,
to keep you going on the train home.
That was kind of him, Daisy. Are you
sure it wasn't meant for you?
No, he did it for Alfred.
I told him we were old friends,
so he did it for you.
You know Ivy turned me down?
I do, yes.
I think I've been a bit blind
where she's concerned.
Love is blind.
Maybe. But I wonder now
I've not been a fool.
You've always been so good to me,
Daisy. So true.
But I could never see it.
That's kind of you to say,
and good to hear.
I loved you, Alfred.
I'll not deny it.
But that's done with now,
and what I felt won't come back.
It's time for you to go your way
and me to go mine.
But you wish me well?
Oh, I do, Alfred, yeah.
So well. So very well.
Friends forever.
Friends forever, Daisy.
Right, now this really is goodbye.
Are you all right, Daisy?
I'll just get this off
and pop in the pantry for my apron.
Well, that's that, then.
Do you know,
when you brought up that basket,...
..I were so proud of you,
I felt like crying out.
If you were my own daughter,
I couldn't be prouder than I am now.
You do know why I came today.
To see the bazaar.
To see you.
I find - perhaps to my surprise -
that since I left,
I can't think of anything but you.
To your surprise and my surprise.
I'm only asking for a chance.
Was there really a conference
in Whitby?
Of course not.
I'm flattered, Charles,
and even moved.
But rather than add to the list
of men I've disappointed,
it might be kinder to refuse you now
and let you off the hook.
Hmm,
I'm afraid I couldn't allow that.
Not without putting up a fight.
What are you still doing here?
I wish I knew what you were up to
yesterday.
Why did you go?
I wanted to get away.
You'd never do anything foolish,
would you?
You'd never risk everything
we've built together?
Certainly not. You know me.
When I do a thing, I like to have
a very good reason for doing it.
Where have you two been hiding?
In plain view,
where all good tricksters hide.
Look what I've found.
Tom, will you see
if there are some clean glasses
on that table?
Well done, my dear. A real triumph.
I hope so.
I've told them
they can clear up the rest tomorrow.
I thought that was the best bazaar
I've known here.
Certainly. At least since
your father and I were running it.
And now, as the Prodigal Husband
home from the sea,
let me raise a glass
to my extraordinary wife
who can clearly manage far better
in my absence. Cora.
Lady Grantham.
Cora. Mama.
Very well done, Lady Grantham. And
now, I'm afraid, I should be going.
It was so kind of you to come.
I don't suppose I could ask YOU
for a lift this time? I came by train
but I'd much rather drive.
Certainly.
I'll see you off.
What sort of menage has that
turned into while I've been away?